

LUCA SONCIN

PYTHON - SQL

I have worked for 10 years as a Mechanical Design Engineer at leading companies across Europe covering Senior-level positions and managing Junior resources for some projects. Since in the past years my inclination and interest in data kept growing, I've decided to become a professional Data Engineer by acquiring most of the core skills for such a role and implementing them with all the knowledge already gained from my previous experiences.

ZKILLZ:

- Python 3 (NumPy¬ Pandas)
- = ZQL
- PyCharm
- MySQL Workbench 8.0
- Visual Studio Code
- GIT / Github
- MS Office
- Agile methodology (Jira)
- Team comms (Teams, Slack, Zoom,

UNDERSTANDING OF:

- Database concepts
- Data pipelines
- ETL/ELT processes
- APIs
- Data visualization
- Cloud platforms (mainly AWS)
- Data warehouses/lakes
- Infrastructure tools

ATTITUDE:

- Commitment to meet deadlines
- Highly numerical and analytical approach
- Proactive and can-do attitude
- Capability to take ownership and
- responsibility of own work
 Capability of communicating with company's personnel at all levels
- Compliance with company and industry standards
- Team leading (whether needed)
- Ability to host meetings
- Strong personal drive
- Enjoy working with data

EXPERIENCE:

- Career transition Feb. 2022 - Present
- Koenigsegg Automotive, SE Jun. 2021 - Feb. 2022 Senior Design, Research & Development Engineer
- NTT Data IT Dec. 2020 - May. 2021 Product Design, Research & Development and Manufacturing Engineer
- Gordon Murray Design J UK Jan. 2020 - Oct. 2020 Senior Mechanical Design Engineer
- Jaguar Land Rover JUK Jan. 2019 - Oct. 2019 Design and Development Engineer
- SM Engineering, IT Aug. 2017 - Dec. 2018 Mechanical Design Engineer
- BE Design IT Jan. 2014 - Jul. 2017 Mechanical Design Team Supervisor & Lead
- Bertone, IT Jan. 2012 - Dec. 2014 Mechanical Design Engineer

EDUCATION:

- English
- Italian
- Spanish (B1)
- Professional Qualification as Mechanical Designer
- Classes at the Psychological Sciences University (2008) & at Foreign Languages and Literatures University
- Scientific High School (A-level) Diploma (2006)

EXPERIENCE (detailed):

- Koenigsegg Automotive, Angelholm, SE (Jun. 2021 Feb. 2022):
 - Project: Koenigsegg Jesko (sport car limited number production)
 - Role: Senior Design, Research & Development Engineer
 - Responsibilities: Deliver ready-for-production vehicle parts
 - Duties: Grant full ownership of certain vehicle components; develop and maintain components database (on excel spreadsheet); scout and liaise with international suppliers; host meetings and coordinate work between different departments; assist other departments with analysis and documentation; comply with company and industry standards; plan timing and costs.

• NTT Data, Milan, IT (Dec. 2020 - May. 2021):

- Project: Vespa Piaggio (Electric scooter prototype)
- Role: Product Design Research & Development and Manufacturing Engineer
- Responsibilities: Design a mechanical prototype with embedded electronic components
- Duties: liaise with international suppliers; host meetings with different departments; assure manufacturing quality and standards; launch prototype tests; integrate crossfunctionality assignments; projects and deliveries; develop pre-project information.

■ Gordon Murray Design, Guildford, UK (Jan. 2020 - Oct. 2020):

- Project: Gordon Murray's T.50 (ultra lightweight sport car production)
- Role: Senior Mechanical Design Engineer
- Responsibilities: Deliver 3D models with manufacturing readiness
- Duties: Engineer a whole system via 3D tools; liaise with suppliers and different departments; develop and maintain components database (on excel spreadsheet); deliver final files into database and systems.

• Jaguar Land Rover, Coventry, UK (Jan. 2019 - Oct. 2019):

- Project: Jaguar E-Type Zero (classic sport car restoration)
- Role: Design and Development Engineer
- Responsibilities: Re-design and develop a mechanical prototype on existing structure
- Duties: Grant full ownership of the project from the Mechanical position; develop and maintain components database (on excel spreadsheet); scout and liaise with international suppliers; host meetings with different departments; assist other departments with analysis and documentation; comply with company and industry standards; produce new design ideas.

• SM Engineering, Turin, IT (Aug. 2017 - Dec. 2018):

- Project: Various (Yamaha, Volkswagen, Nissan)
- Role: Mechanical Design Engineer
- Responsibilities: Deliver 3D models with manufacturing readiness
- Duties: Engineer whole systems via 3D tools; liaise with suppliers and different departments; maintain components database (on excel spreadsheet); file name creation and organization; deliver final files into database and systems.

■ BE Design, Turin, IT (Jan. 2014 - Jul. 2017):

- Project: Various (Mahindra, Alfa Romeo, Thunder Power, Be's electric vehicles)
- Role: Mechanical Design Engineer and Team Supervisor & Lead
- Responsibilities: Deliver 3D models with manufacturing readiness / Guide and supervise Junior team
- Duties: Engineer whole systems via 3D tools; liaise with suppliers and different departments; maintain components database (on excel spreadsheet); file name creation and organization; deliver final files into database and systems.
 Supervise; guide and teach a junior team; develop a whole vehicle from scratch.

• Bertone, Turin, IT (Jan. 2012 - Dec. 2014):

- Project: Koenigsegg Jesko (sport car limited number production)
- Role: Mechanical Design Engineer
- Responsibilities: Deliver 3D models with manufacturing readiness
- Duties: Engineer whole systems via 3D tools; liaise with suppliers and different departments; maintain components database (on excel spreadsheet); deliver final files into database and systems.